Guide to the Thomas E. Daley papers, 1919-1952 UA 334
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Thomas E. Daley papers
1919-1929, 1942-1952
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Daley, Thomas E.
UA 334
2 Linear Feet 3 boxes
The Daley Papers include personal documents from Daley's high school and Rice University years, a play script and original artwork. There are also photographs of Rice and of World War II infantry and intelligence units, along with some newspaper clippings and correspondence from 1946 and 1963.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Ellis Daley (1907-1973), born in Arizona, graduated from and was editor of the Rice University yearbook in 1929. He was an artist who worked in advertising after graduation and enlisted in the army in 1942. He was married to Dorothy Moulton (1913-2011), a 1934 Rice graduate who was employed by Woodfill Real Estate in Houston. The couple donated to Rice University; the Daley American and European Glass Collection was bequeathed to the Houston Heritage Society.
Scope and Contents
The Daley Papers include personal documents from Daley's high school and Rice University years, a play script and original artwork. There are also photographs of Rice and of World War II infantry and intelligence units, along with some newspaper clippings and correspondence from 1946 and 1963.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michael R. Daley, 2015.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Social life and customs; World War (1939-1945); Theater
Document Types
photographs
Places
Rice University; Art
- Series I: Schooling, 174271
  - Harrisburg [TX] High School, 1924, 174272 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vesper George School of Art, Boston, MA, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rice Institute, 1925-1927
    - Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Events (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Class papers (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Images, 174280
  - High School photos (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rice Institute, c. 1929, photos, 174281 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Army photos (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Army panoramas, 174282
    - 44A Infantry, Cos. H,I,J, 1943, 174283 (Drawer 69)
    - Squadron I Thirteenth Course Intelligence Division, 174284 (Drawer 69)
    - 384th Infantry, Cos. G,H,I, 174285 (Drawer 69)
  - Wedding film (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series III: Army
  - Orders, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commendations, travel, medical, courses, Scientific Advisory Group, Officer Candidate School yearbook, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Promotions, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Discharge, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Reserves, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Personal
  - Will, product endorsement, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Artwork created for various publications (Box 2)
    - 1934 football schedule (Box 2)
    - Book plate (Box 2)
    - Dance program covers for Rice Galveston Club 1926 & 1927, Rice Junior Prom 1931, Rice May Fete 1933 (Box 2)
    - Cover for Rice Owl 1935; pages from Rice Campanile 1929 (Box 2)
    - Bound issues of Rice Owl, vol. 6, 1927-28 (Box 2)
    - Proof boards submitted to New Yorker magazine (with rejection notice): 1. "but Duchess wouldn't your husband object to your smoking?" 2. "Toots is our name Twiddie?" 3. "Why mom, it's a party by the name of Schultz" 4. "Duchess, you hadn't had this operation the night the Duke introduced us" 5. "Toots, is our name Spivvy?" 6. not labelled (Box 2)
- Series V: Dorothy Moulton Daley [sister]
  - Scrapbook: Saint Agnes Academy, Houston, TX, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook: Harrisburg High School, 1919 (Box 3)